<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gergelj.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://gergelj.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-09-05T19:57:01+00:00</updated><id>https://gergelj.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">teaching experience</title><link href="https://gergelj.github.io/blog/2021/teaching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="teaching experience"/><published>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gergelj.github.io/blog/2021/teaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gergelj.github.io/blog/2021/teaching/"><![CDATA[<p>During my undergraduate studies, I had the opportunity to teach my fellow students as an assistant to the teaching assistant—essentially a teaching fellow. Throughout the semester, I was available to assist students, particularly when they had intriguing questions. I served as a teaching assistant for one semester in the subject of Computer Architecture, where students worked on programming exercises in assembly language. <em>Ouch!</em></p> <p><em>The crux of the matter</em>: Make sure you have a solid grasp of C programming before diving into Computer Architecture!</p> <p>Later, during my master’s studies, I became a teaching assistant for database-related subjects, including relational databases, non-relational databases, object-oriented programming with database elements, database design, normalization, and data organization. This role spanned two semesters: one for online courses and one for in-person classes. As someone who is naturally shy and doesn’t enjoy performing in front of large groups, starting with online courses was a great fit. Teaching in-person classes proved more challenging but also more engaging.</p> <p>Being a teaching assistant not only allowed me to teach and assess students’ knowledge but also provided valuable insights into the teaching process itself.</p> <p>Teaching involves sharing knowledge, answering questions, listening, and debating. It also requires preparing study materials and tests, utilizing teaching tools (such as projectors, smart boards, PCs/laptops, printers, and copiers), and staying organized in front of hundreds of students.</p> <p><em>The crux of the matter</em>: If you’re a student, give your teaching assistant some slack. They’re doing their best for you while managing a busy schedule with multiple classes each week.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="experience"/><category term="teaching"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the crux of the matter]]></summary></entry></feed>